♪ ♪
So, Mr. Beloit, you would
like this court to believe
that your brother, the
defendant, Tom Beloit,
could not have
killed his wife's lover
because he was
with you that night.
That's right.
Uh-huh.
Who drove to the bar you
allegedly went to that night,
you or your brother?
What do you mean, "allegedly"?
Huh?
We were there.
Just answer the question,
please, Mr. Beloit.
I drove.
And whose car did you
drive, yours or your brother's?
Mine. Look...
I already told the cops.
Tom and I drove to the Cedar Bar
to check out a
singer for our club.
We got there around 10:00.
We left around 11:00,
after she finished her set.
And then you drove home
in your car, is that correct?
Yes.
But you can't identify
one single person
who saw you there
that night, can you?
It was Friday night!
The place was jammed.
But we were there.
And your car was
there, too, right?
How many times I have to say it?
Mr. Beloit, are you aware
that perjury is a crime
for which there are
severe penalties?
I'm telling the truth.
You own a bar, Mr. Beloit.
Is it true what they say,
that customers come in
and tell you their troubles?
Yeah. Yeah, that's true.
And sometimes you tell them
your troubles, too, don't you?
I talked to some of the
customers at your bar,
and according to them,
you complain that your car
is always in the
shop... Is that true?
I got a lemon.
And that's where your car
was on the night of the murder...
In the shop.
I have a copy of the
work order right here.
Uh... uh...
Don't... do it, Mr. Beloit.
Don't get yourself in deeper.
You didn't go anywhere
with your brother that night.
You weren't even with your
brother that night, were you?
Yes...
you love your brother,
and you want to help him.
And we can understand
that, but you must not lie
for him.
He wasn't with you that night...
because that night,
he was, in fact...
murdering his wife's lover.
Ladies and
gentlemen of the jury,
have you reached a verdict?
Yes, we have, Your Honor.
The defendant will please rise.
May we have your
verdict, please?
We, the jury, find the
defendant, Thomas Beloit,
guilty of murder
in the first degree.
Tommy... Tommy...
Tommy, don't worry.
Ms. March! Ms. March!
JULIE: Thank you.
Not right now. Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
Excuse us. Coming through. Excuse us.
Congratulations. Hey, thanks!
I know!
Julie? Julie?
Mike Eiseman.
What brings you to Atlanta?
I'm just passing through.
Um, well, I'm on
vacation, sort of.
My mother's down in
Florida visiting her sister,
so she wants me to drive
down and bring her back,
so I thought I would stop,
uh, on the way to... see you.
Well, Atlanta isn't
exactly on your way.
Oh, Mike,
this is Eli Boward, an
attorney in my office.
Mike Eiseman, an
old friend of mine.
Hi.
Um, listen, you wouldn't, uh,
by any chance be free
for, you know, lunch, or...?
Well...
Uh, gee, Mike,
I'm sorry, uh, Julie and I
are having a working lunch.
We've just been assigned
to the Branca case.
Oh, Mike, I'm sorry.
No, oh, you know, I mean,
you know, I mean, I
should have called and...
But let's talk before
you go, okay?
Where are you staying?
Um, the Grand Hotel.
Bye.
Grand. Bye.
Branca case! Mm-hmm.
You just convicted
an innocent man, lady!
You just convicted an innocent
man. A jury of his peers convicted...
No, you! You did it!
You did it! The jury
believed your lie!
Okay, okay, hey,
hey, hold it. Hey! Hey!
Hey!
Nobody railroads my
brother and gets away with it.
Mr. Beloit, I know you're upset.
What's going on?
I'm gonna get you for this!
What is he talking
about... "get you"?
Oh, he's just...
Are-Are you all right?
I'm fine, I'm fine. Hi, Eli. Hi.
You don't look all right.
It's all right; I'm okay.
Did... Did-Did that
guy threaten you?
His brother was just
convicted of murder,
so he's kind of upset.
Oh, that's right, your case.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
If-If that guy threatened you,
don't you think you
should file a report?
No, no, he was just
blowing off steam.
Hello?
Who is this?
Hello, Julie. It's me.
Who are you, and why are you
following...
It's white tablet paper,
black permanent marker.
You can buy them
in any grocery store.
I'll send it over to the lab,
but I doubt that
they'll find prints.
There's not much we can
do in a situation like this.
Bob, the man was in my garage.
And-And he called me
so many times last night,
I had to disconnect the phone.
Well, Julie, I need
proof that it's Nick Beloit.
He threatened me
in front of witnesses.
Threats aren't proof of a crime.
You, of all people, know that.
Look, let me work
on the note. Uh,
if there's anything
there, I'll be all over him.
Uh, Julie... I'm sorry.
Yes, yes.
We all know the law.
But the man has my phone number.
And he knows where I live.
I don't know what to do.
I'll...
I'll put Conrad on it.
If this Nick Beloit
harasses you again,
we'll get him.
Okay?
Um... uh, uh,
m-meantime, w-what
would you think of...
staying with me?
Oh, okay with me.
All right.
That'd take care of the
mysterious phone calls
and anonymous notes.
Did you sleep any?
Not a wink. Oh.
Well... Well, let's...
let's go pack a bag.
No.
What? No.
I can't do it. Well...
I'm not going to give
him the satisfaction
of driving me out
of my own home.
At least, not yet.
Let's... Let's give it
another 24 hours, and
maybe he'll go away.
Do you think that's wise?
I don't know.
Hello?
You look lovely in blue.
If you think you're
frightening me, Mr. Beloit,
you're wrong.
And if you keep this up,
sooner or later, you're
going to make a mistake,
and that's when
I'm going to nail you.
And then you are going to
join your brother in prison.
And now the show is over.
You all right? I'm all right.
I just panicked. I'm sorry.
Oh, don't be sorry.
Somebody peeping in your window.
Must be in that high-rise
across the street.
Yeah.
Conrad will be
there. You packed?
Almost. Okay.
Ben, I've given this a
great deal of thought.
I'm going to stay at your house,
but I'm going to go
to work in the morning.
Julie!
I am going to do my job.
I am not going to
let this disrupt my life.
Well, c-couldn't you
take a few days off?
No.
Well, what-what,
what-what... I know...
Wh-what if you leave
your work clothes here?
Let's go.
Well, I'll take the bag.
Good morning.
Oh, good morning. Hey.
Did you sleep?
Yes. Good.
At first, I didn't
think I would,
and then, all of a
sudden, it was morning.
Phone didn't ring once.
Maybe he got
tired and it's over.
Yeah.
This will be ready in a minute.
Oh... I don't eat breakfast.
You have to eat breakfast.
It's the most important
meal of the day.
You sound like my mother.
Well, you can bet your sweet
patootie I'm not your mother.
But you got to eat breakfast.
Oh, Ben, Eli and I
have the Branca case.
Yeah? Yeah, yeah.
And we blocked out the
whole day to work on it together.
Yeah, yeah.
So I, uh, guess I better go.
Well, wait a minute... uh...
Here.
There.
Egg sandwich.
If you starve to death,
it won't be my fault.
Thank you. Yeah.
Hello?
Anybody there?
Hello!
This is the only apartment
on this side of the building...
that's been rented
in the last month?
Yeah, the last six months.
Guess she hasn't moved in yet.
She?
Yeah.
Rented it to a woman.
Name's, um...
Lisa Johnson.
Mannish kind of dame.
Tall, dark hair, about
down to her shoulders,
plain dress, below the knee.
Didn't talk much.
Had kind of a low voice,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
Anyway, the name's Lisa Johnson.
At least that's the
name she gave me.
Paid me in cash, so I
didn't ask any questions.
"Never look a gift horse
in the mouth," I always say.
You know what I mean? Yeah.
When did she rent it?
Last Tuesday.
Phone works.
You have her former address,
her work number, anything?
She paid cash.
Okay.
If you hear from Lisa Johnson,
you give me a call.
A man of principle.
Yeah.
Come in.
Oh, hi, Eli.
Are you all right?
Fine.
Is something wrong?
Well, um... you were
due in court at 10:30.
Motions... the Branca case.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, no, no, it's all
right. I took care of it.
How could I have done that?
It's right here in my calendar.
How could I just forget?
Julie, look, why don't
you take some time off,
get away for a while.
Now, Paula and I have
a place in the country,
up near Jasper, and
you are welcome to it.
Oh, thanks, Eli, but
I need to stay here.
At work, I feel like I
have some sort of control.
Mm-hmm.
I mean, I did.
I won't forget anything
again, I promise.
Okay.
But you remember,
any time you want to
use the place, it's all right.
And Paula says so, too.
Thanks.
Hello. Who is this?
Well, yes, it is.
Who is this?
Oh, um...
Well, just a minute, uh...
Michael Eiseman.
Hi.
Are you still in town?
Oh...
no, tonight's not very good.
Uh, tomorrow...
Uh, Mike, to be honest with you,
I'm going through a rough
time at work right now and...
Well, if I change my
mind, I'll call you, okay?
Are you still at
the Grand Hotel?
Room 817.
Okay. Okay.
Bye.
What'll it be?
Can I get a beer?
$1.75.
You know a woman
named Lisa Johnson?
No.
Lives in an apartment
on Ashton and Third.
What are you asking me for?
That's halfway across town.
She come in here?
That's what I heard.
No, don't know her.
Yeah.
Got a match?
That's interesting.
Not many people
light matches that way.
Found this in an apartment
on Ashton and Third.
I don't know what your story is,
but you got something to say,
why don't you just say it.
Bye.
Hello?
Hi. How you doing?
Oh... Ben.
I did something today I've
never done before in my life.
What?
Well, I was supposed
to be at court at 10:30,
and I forgot all about it.
Oh, I heard about that.
You did?
Yeah.
You know how fast word
travels around the courthouse.
Who told you?
Charlie.
The hot dog vendor?
Yeah.
Hey, speaking of food...
I'll cook.
It's the least I can do.
I'll stop by the market
on my way home.
What market?
I'll meet you there.
Oh, you don't have to do that.
I just like to look at the
produce and push the cart.
The Food Mart on Carson.
Okay, I'll meet you there.
And I'll get us a cart
that all the wheels work.
Okay.
Julie, it's okay. It's me.
It's Nick Beloit!
He's right behind me!
He got away. Oh!
Julie, are you sure
it was Nick Beloit?
Yes.
Well, I didn't get a
look at his face, but...
I just came from the bar
he and his brother
own... He was working.
There's no way that he could
have beaten me here. No way.
But if it wasn't Nick Beloit...
who was it?
This is good.
Yeah, I've had that a long time.
All right, let's say it wasn't
Nick Beloit in that apartment.
Could have been a friend of his.
Maybe.
Like the woman that
rented that apartment.
It could have been a friend.
Maybe... or maybe it has
nothing to do with Nick Beloit.
You found the matchbook
with the matches folded down.
Nick Beloit was
in that apartment.
Or somebody who wanted
us to think it was Nick Beloit.
Who... Who else was around
when he threatened you?
Who wasn't around?
The corridor was packed.
Well, think back.
Does anybody in
particular come to mind?
You were there... Yeah.
Eli...
Harvey Goodman...
that's Tom Beloit's lawyer...
And... Oh, there was this
friend of mine from Baltimore,
Michael Eiseman.
He, um, just showed
up out of the blue.
And he said he was on
his way down to Florida.
He called me yesterday.
He's still in town.
But that's... that's
just a coincidence.
He's a legal secretary.
We worked together in Baltimore.
Oh... Oh, just-just a friend.
I think he did ask me out once.
Did you go? No.
No, no.
I remember I was very surprised
because I never thought of
Mike as somebody I'd ever date.
But I didn't go.
And he never asked me again.
Yeah...
Yeah, well, uh...
Uh, I wonder if-if
we should, um...
It can't be him.
It just can't be.
Julie...?
This is such a nice surprise.
I thought you might've
gone back to Florida.
Not yet.
Something's bothering you.
Why do you say that?
I can tell.
I-I used to watch
you a lot in the office,
and I know when you're upset.
Why did you watch me, Mike?
You're pretty.
Did I do something wrong?
Are you mad at me?
No, no, I'm not mad at you.
But, uh...
I do have a problem.
Somebody... a man...
Has been calling
me and following me.
Oh, you think it's me?
I don't know.
Julie, I would never ever
do anything to upset you.
Mike, I'm not accusing you.
It's just that...
all of this started the
day you came to Atlanta.
Oh.
So you can understand
why I have to ask you.
Why did you come to see me?
I-I wanted to
take you to dinner,
and... thank you.
You... You helped me, years ago.
Oh, Mike.
I only treated you like
I treat everybody else.
No, you were always so nice.
I'm different; I'm... I'm shy.
It's not easy for me to
make friends with women.
And you were so nice.
It meant a great deal to me.
I don't know what to say.
Well... I've made
friends with a lady.
Um... she's shy, too.
I don't know what to say.
You don't have to say anything.
You do believe me,
though, don't you?
Yes, I believe you.
Ben?
Yeah, in here.
Hey. Hey. She go see him?
Yeah.
It figures.
Everything okay?
Did you stay close?
Didn't have to.
They never left the
lobby of the hotel.
No? No.
No, they talked a while,
then she left, and he went
into the hotel restaurant,
ate this big bowl of
cereal with sliced bananas
and then went up to his room.
In the middle of the afternoon?
Yeah. I watched him
eat the whole bowl,
then watched him
go up to his room.
Even listened for him to
snap that little security chain.
What kind of bird is he?
I don't know, he's
a little... little weird.
He's average.
Hmm.
He could be the one.
Could be. Yeah.
Well, this place is
clean as a whistle.
Oh, uh... well,
what do you think?
Whoever we're looking for,
he'd come in here...
he'd sit there waiting
for Julie to come home,
he'd use the phone to harass her
and then he'd leave. Yep.
One other thing he might've
done while he was waiting.
What?
What's that?
When you drop a
phone book like that,
it'll open up to the page
that's used the most.
And I bet it opened up
to the restaurant section.
Yeah.
Any man...
who waits for hours
has food delivered.
You like pizza?
Hi.
Julie?
Julie, where are you?
I'm in here. Oh.
Boy!
Somebody washed the curtains...
the windows...
and everything!
I did.
Why?
Because everything was dirty.
I just can't sit around
and do nothing.
I'll go nuts.
Uh...
What if I took you to lunch?
I fixed some tuna
salad. It's in the fridge.
Um, Julie, you've got to
stop cleaning that oven.
I gotta keep busy.
It's self-cleaning.
I knew that.
Oh.
Well, here, sit down
and I'll fix you some lemonade.
Hello.
Let me talk to Julie.
Who?
Come on...
You got the wrong number.
I know she's there.
Who are you?
The pizza man.
Well, listen, pizza man,
let me tell you something...
You...!
Damn.
The pizza man?
That night he was looking
through your window,
while he was waiting for you to
come home, he ordered a pizza.
We went to a lot of places,
but we never... never
found anybody who saw him.
He was like "The Shadow."
He knows I'm here.
How did he find out?
How? I don't know. I... I...
I didn't tell anybody
I was staying here.
Not a single soul. How
did he find out? I... I...
I don't know. Now he's
following both of us.
Here, sit down...
I don't want to sit down!
I want to get that guy!
I want...
I... I just want my life back.
I know. I know.
I know.
Everything's gonna be all right.
We've got to find
you another place...
where you'll be safe.
Doesn't Eli have a
place somewhere?
Look, I don't know
what you're talking about.
Trespassing, harassment,
maybe even assault.
Hey, if somebody is
harassing that broad,
I say great.
More power to him.
It isn't me.
Well, if it isn't you,
somebody's doing his best
to make it look like you.
How many people know you
bend your matches over this way?
Everybody who's
ever seen me smoke.
After you threatened Julie
March at the courthouse,
where'd you go?
Went home, changed
clothes, came straight here.
Most of your customers regulars?
Yeah, yeah, except on weekends.
The day your
brother was convicted,
you remember seeing anybody
come in here you didn't know?
Not right off.
Nah, I don't know; I don't know.
I want you to come downtown
and look over some pictures.
Here's the address.
What kind of pictures?
Oh, ex-cons, parolees,
people who don't
like Julie March much.
I could be there all day.
You could be in
prison a lot longer.
9:00 a.m.
This is so nice.
Yeah. Yeah, it is, isn't it?
You know, we
better head back in.
It looks like we're
in for a storm.
Come on.
Are you sure
you don't need me back in town?
I'm positive.
Oh! I wish I could work,
but all my files
are in the office.
Well, I can go back
into town tonight,
pick up what you
need, and then bring it
to you tomorrow... oh, boy.
That would be great!
Oh, thank you.
And thank Paula, too,
for lending me your place.
That's okay. Come on!
We're in for it! Let's go!
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh, I'm soaked!
Check the, uh, dresser
in the bedroom upstairs.
Paula may have left
some sweaters here, huh?
It's freezing!
I'll, uh, start a fire, huh?
♪ ♪
Hi.
I... I found this in the drawer.
Everything in here is about me.
Yeah.
I think a lot of you, Julie.
Where is Paula?
Gone.
I'm glad you're here.
Eli, you're very upset.
No, no, I'm not.
I don't get upset, Julie.
And besides, you're here now.
You know, it took me quite
a while, but you are here.
Isn't there somebody
you could talk to,
like a doctor or a close friend?
Somebody you could call...?
I'll talk to you. No...
No, this isn't right.
Yes.
Oh, yes, it is.
Julie, you saw my scrapbook.
You don't know how often
I have dreamed
of having you here.
It is going to be so
wonderful now, Julie.
It's just...
the two of us together.
You and me...
so close...
touching.
You and me, Julie.
Just you and me.
I have to go.
Don't you understand?
I think about you all the time.
Eli, we can talk about
this another time.
No!
You're going to stay.
You want to.
I have to go.
Ow!
Oh!
You're staying.
You are not going to leave me.
You're here. You are here.
Do you understand me, hmm?
Yes, yes...
Don't make me angry.
Don't... do that, hmm?
No, no, no.
What about this guy?
Do you recognize this guy?
Uh...
Well... this guy?
Here you go.
Uh, nope.
Fresh from the photo lab.
Oh, good, good, good, good.
Take a look at this guy.
You recognize him?
Nope.
You sure?
Yep.
Have you spoken to Julie?
I tried to call and
the phone was busy.
This guy looks familiar.
That's Eli Boward.
He works with Julie.
She was with him
outside the courtroom.
She was?
Well, so was I.
I was so mad, all I
remember seeing is her.
Well, well, come over here.
Come over here.
Try this guy.
What about this guy?
I'm telling you, I've
seen that guy before,
and it wasn't in that
courtroom either.
Napoleon brandy.
This guy came in my
place three nights in a row,
sat down at the end of the
bar drinking Napoleon brandy.
Are you sure?
I finally remember, now
you don't believe me?
You got, you got
gas in your car?
Enough to get us there.
Don't try to run away again.
Don't do that.
You see, I don't understand.
I thought if I
brought you up here,
you would want to be here,
you would want to
be with me all the way.
Well, you will, you will.
Right. You will, you will.
It just takes some people
longer than others, that's all.
I mean, I can wait.
I can be patient.
But, of course, you
already knew that, huh?
You are going to
want to be with me.
It'll be good.
Don't.
Now, don't...
Eli?
Ben Matlock.
Eli, what's going on?!
Well, you already know, Ben.
Get back in your car.
Aw, come on, Eli.
Just let me talk
with you for a minute.
No, get back in your car, Ben.
Eli, you don't want
to hurt anybody.
Get out of here!
There'll be other people coming.
You can't run 'em all off.
Julie!
Well, I'll be damned... Eli.
You never know, do you?
I'll call the police.
Yeah.
You all right?
I don't know.
You look good, anyway.
Let's go home.
Let's do that.
www.tvsubtitles.net